TIKAM ALMA | RESUME

FullStack Developer | Security Developer

Status: B.tech, IT and ICT, DAIICT Gandhinagar

Fields: Full-Stack Web Devlopment, Security Development, Bug-Bounty Hunting, Machine Learning

Prefers: JS, Python, Node.js, React.js, Django, C/C++, Linux, Git,

Activities: OWASP Project Developer, Bughiest Site Engineer, Security+ML Research, Portrait Artist

Linkedin https://github.com/Tikam02 tikamalma1@gmail.com +91 8154940247

Summary

Undergraduate student at DAIICT-Gandhinagar, Bachelors Degree:ICT. Currently working on open-source projects of Open Web Application Security projects and frameworks. Machine Learning enthusiast, learning and implementing. Researching on topics of Cyber Security and machine learning to blend it.

Experience

Part Time Site-Engineer - https://www.bugheist.com/

May 2018 - Present

- · Fullstack website opensource contributor and developer of Bug-Logging Tool:Bughiest
- · Implemented new frontend+backend in Djnago.
- · Implemented frameworks like Djano-tellme, Django-postman etc.

Rural Internship - http://hifeed.org/

December 2017

- · Exposure to the rural villages and solved their problems.
- · Built a forum and communication website for self-help Woman's community for their easy communication and spreading awareness.
- · Worked, survey and implemented solutions to the problems of vocational and educational training in rural areas.

Security Developer Intern - https://www.owasp.org

June 2017 - August2017

- · Selected as and intern for open web application security- Offensive Web Testing Framework(OWTF-Project)
- · Implemented SSH testing and network protocols.
- · Framework vulnerability testing and Django UI/UX implementation

Projects

Network Security+ML - https://github.com/Tikam02/MLSec

May 2018-Present

- ML based network analyzer
- · Technologoy will be used:Tensorflow+Pandas+Numpy+Scikit+Wireshark+Snort.
- · Purpose:To learn network and packet analysis through machine learning

Top Trends - https://github.com/Tikam02/Top-Trends

Mar 2018-May 2018

- · Top-Trends is Python+Django based Fullstack internet web crawler that crawls through site and updates trending stories and articles
- · Technology:Python+Scipy+Scikit+Pandas+Numpy+Bootstrap
- · Purpose:To implement a full stack rest framework with crawler.

Wine Shop - https://github.com/Tikam02/Wine-Shop

Jan 2018-Feb 2018

- · Machine Learning based recommendation engine using K-means clustering algorithm.
- · Tech Used:Python+Django+bootstrap.
- · Purpose:Learning and implementation of basic ML algorithms.

Education

- DAIICT-Gandhinagar 2016-2020

- · Undergraduate Student:ICT
- · Developer student Community
- · Activities:Basketball,Portrait Sketching,Books